the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet will exam of
holography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of Hull talk
for the week of October 25th 1999. my
guest this week is Bill Pugh and Bill
was on the state committee that had the
task of rewriting the state of Florida's
communication technology standards
those standards which will be followed
by every High School in the State of
Florida now includes holography Bill's
going to come on and fill us in on how
it all got started what were the selling
points to get it passed and where it's
headed
so let's move on to the interview with
Bill I'm not going to come back on after
the interview so I will thank you now
for tuning in and I invite you to come
back each and every week
for another week of holotalk as we
continue to have guests throughout this
1999-2000 holotalk season so here's the
interview with Bill right after this
message
thank you
would you like to create your own
three-dimensional Holograms where you
can begin today and Frankie Freitas can
show you how from introductory guides
like a shoebox philosophy system to
developing Innovative and affordable new
laser systems along with year-round
holography Workshop programs Frank is
finding a way to bring the attic reach
into the reach of everyone from
September through May you can attend one
of his free even lecture series at the
studio in Allentown Pennsylvania which
is a quick non-stop drive from the New
York Philadelphia Baltimore and
Washington DC areas offered the first
Wednesday of every month thank
evening at 7 30 with a total holography
followed by a tour of the lab and a
chance to view Holograms in his personal
collection there is no cost to attend
the Wednesday evening lecture but you
must call in advance or send an email to
make reservations to reach the studio
for more information or to make
reservations for the Wednesday evening
lecture series please call toll-free
1-800-458-35
[Music]
two five or send an email from the
website that number again is
1-800-458-3525 to attend a Wednesday
evening lecture at the studio Frank hope
to see you there
foreign
[Music]
I've got you on the right line now do I
understand that you've got some big news
that we're going to put on the whole
talk show especially for students and
Educators in Florida area but I imagine
that this is something that could be
looked at nationally as well uh yes I do
I just came back from Orlando working
with a group of approximately 13
Communications technology teachers and
we rewrote the communications technology
Frameworks and starting next year in the
State of Florida calligraphy will become
part of the Florida state standards and
Communications technology now this will
be something that will be practiced in
all the schools then yes it will it will
be offered in uh all the high schools
through the State of Florida and you did
this you came up to the lab for a
workshop a while ago over the summer is
it over the summer yes it was it was
then it was in July I came up okay yeah
came up there and I was very impressed
with the workshop I was I'm very
impressed with the technology and not
just the technical part of process but
also the academic process the physics
the chemistry the math and that's one of
the things that sold the process with
the director of technology in the State
of Florida was that we weren't just wood
butchering something that we were
meeting with or or come or working with
are folks in the academic areas and
bringing in this new technology now if I
remember correctly your school district
is basically very high technology
oriented to begin with right like the
school district is but our particular
School Inglewood High School in
Jacksonville uh we have probably one of
the finest facilities in the State of
Florida we have a technology studies lab
we have material processing lab we have
the communications lab and then we also
have a drafting Design Lab with full CAD
facilities and everything we're very
lucky we have very good support from our
Administration in our particular School
you do credit the administration for
most of these advances in technology
education in that school I would imagine
right yes I would I've been at the
school since at this particular school
since 1987. I'm on my fifth principal I
don't know if it's because of me or if
it's just a stepping ground for them
but it seems like they get better as
they go
and also our technology department at
Inglewood High School We're very
professional we we don't consider
ourselves as the typical shot teacher
you know we put ourselves at the same
level as the academic people and we
believe that our courses are as
important and the things that we teach
you know is as important as what they
teach
do you approach this in your school as
sort of a career type of education where
you're preparing students for to go out
into the workforce and take on the
responsibility of a career in these
fields uh no it's more of an exploratory
in the skill centers in the State of
Florida The Vocational areas do the job
preparation in the technology area our
main concern or our mission is to
um to explore the kids to create
interest with them so that they go
further on after they get out of high
school if it's to a junior college or
university or a technical school or
apprenticeship program it's just to give
them a chance to see what is available
in all particular areas but that doesn't
mean that some of our students don't
come right out of high school and get
some pretty good jobs yeah what did you
do that made you successful with this
well I think a couple things I think
that we at the school consider ourselves
as professionals like I said before
we we do the extra we we do what we need
to do with the kids we just don't come
in at 7 30 and leave it at 2
uh besides that it was a preparation of
being able to show the other areas that
we can integrate with that it wasn't
just something that could be done in my
particular lab that would help the
students it wasn't just a silk screen
shirt that they were Printing and
carrying home I showed them through your
help and all the information you gave me
and and you are a major part of getting
this in uh I was able to show them how
it how we brought in chemistry how we
brought in a variety of physics how we
brought in the map how we bring in the
teamwork Concepts how all this can be
integrated it's not just just my kids
that will be working with this but the
science teachers that in my particular
school right now want to bring their
kids down they want to bring their
physics kids down into my darkroom
and to you know to work with the lasers
and you know the different processes
that that we'll be doing what are your
future plans for the project do you see
this moving beyond these small shoebox
philography type of setup that you're
getting started with and moving on to
larger labs and more advanced work I've
already planned that I've already I'm
already designing my sand tables and uh
trying to finagle to get some bigger
lasers in and my students have gone
crazy I mean they are absolutely driving
me mad and and that's one of the things
that's that's sold this with the other
Educators lives with this weekend I took
down plates that my kids shot and I said
look look at this and they couldn't
believe it it was just they thought that
this was just such a a on foreseeing
technology that could be done in a high
school
yeah it's a wonderful program holography
has and not just because that's my thing
but holography really does have so much
to offer to so many different peoples
with so many different backgrounds and
interests that there's something for
everyone and especially in a team effort
where you don't have one person doing
everything you've got specific people
doing specific tasks and you can really
bring in a very wide spectrum of
interests and abilities and have them
all work together with holography well
that's one of the processes I see at my
school I can take the I guess a
quote-unquote honor student with the
with the
low performing academic student
put them in group two or three of them
together and they all have something
that they can give the team the
so-called low performing academic
students might not
be able to figure out the math or the
chemistry but they gonna he can get that
lens and that laser lined up perfect to
shoot that play yeah whereas the other
kids you hire kids you know they can set
you know do the chemistry and mixed
chemistry and things like that so it
and and the good part about it is the
two different kids are mixing real well
because all of a sudden this kid isn't a
dummy or this kid isn't a nerd yeah you
know and and it's really beginning to
help the kids that way and we all would
have wind up mixing with each other when
they get out into the real world anyway
in real world work situations exactly
yeah exactly now this this technology
curriculum standards that was just
Rewritten and when was it re-written
left uh approximately I'm gonna say
probably 10 years ago 10 to 12 years ago
and it will be 10 to 12 years before
it's written again
so we had to uh you know cut a lot of
the old or dilute some of the old to
bring some of the new yeah yeah and I
would imagine we're going to see a lot
more change in the next 10 years than we
did in the past 10 years as well oh
definitely you know things just move in
such a rapid clip anymore exactly almost
daily sometimes on the uh with
electronic communication
yeah we brought in see our Frameworks
had zero or very little on even
computers I mean when it was written
before computers weren't even used in
the classroom it wasn't thought of yeah
so we had to bring in the full
electronic generating type you know of
imagery and we're going to continue to
work together and as you begin to
advance with your lab down there we can
eventually bring your computers into the
holographic process as well but that's
one of the things that I want to do also
yeah right I mean I'm just I'm like a
kid at Christmas time and a lot of the
Educators that I was with this weekend
uh were basically the same I was talking
to Doug Wagner
the director of Technology education for
the State of Florida and he had found
out what I was doing in my high school
and he basically he said you see that
that gets into this framework
it's very interesting because someone
whom I was speaking to about this had
mentioned to me that whatever Florida
does you will find Texas and California
following right on the Hills usually
that's the case or what they do you
usually find us doing because of the I
guess the ability to
to get at that Cutting Edge what is it
about Florida Texas and California that
are in intermixed with each other with
education I think one of the things is
because of all the the type of Industry
that we have I see with NASA and a lot
of the military bases and all
uh in Central Florida in Orlando where
we were of course Mickey Mouse has has
created the school system down there
that is just fun I know I was in the lab
just today as a matter of fact I've I
called you when I walked in the door I
was so excited about this
um I was in a television production lab
down in Dr Phillips High School in
Orlando Florida and this is a a facility
that any any News broadcasting
Department would love to have I mean I
it was just cute rooms beautiful sets
and it was all because of Universal
Studios and all down there they they
went out they talked to them and you
know they're getting a lot of Grants and
things that way so I think that there's
a lot of technology in these three
states between
like I said between NASA and the
military and all that you know that
creates these things that's wonderful
and it's a nice it's a great day for
holography as well and uh this is what
we need to keep things moving forward
exactly and don't forget I don't know if
you got the last email but there is a uh
a new section on the website there on
making their own plates yeah yes I I saw
that and matter of fact I printed it up
and I was discussing it with another
teacher here at school
um are they going to
break down the uh the the chemistry that
that's going in are they going to give
the mixture of the chemicals
is telling the the what chemicals are
being used yeah not what percentages of
these uh did you get the worksheet as
well yeah yes but I didn't I didn't
notice the uh maybe I just overlooked it
I think I don't even think anything's
mixed I think it's just individual bags
but I'll have to double check and
re-look at that and send Jeff an email
and ask me a question about that okay
yeah I've got to talk because especially
at the high school level if we can mix
our own you know make our own plates and
all I mean just the expense of it would
you know really help us out yeah yeah
it's it's getting to be very exciting
once again yeah well bill I want to
thank you for I don't want to hold you
up on the line here I want to thank you
very much for calling in with the
information and we'll get this up for a
program of whole talk and I'm sure
Educators across the country will be
very interested in in keeping the blast
of this development and how will they be
able to keep abreast of this the
Frameworks that we
um develop this weekend uh will be take
to Tallahassee the Doug Wagner will
place those on the internet where the
educators of Florida will be able to
hand anyone else will be able to look at
them and then
um it will go into effect next year yeah
so it will be there uh
as the progression that goes on from my
end here in Duval County and what I can
find out throughout the state I will
definitely be emailing you okay I'm
calling you all night great yeah and
we'll get together with your students
over the internet as well for a question
and answer session and a number of other
technology things too that'll be great
yeah and I want to do a little bit of
videoing and uh send that to you too
that's great being see the kids working
but I want to once again I want to thank
you again because if you hadn't prepared
me with the information that I needed I
could have made this sale job
my pleasure you were the culprit I hope
you enjoy your trip you you did you say
that you drove straight through no you
didn't drive straight through up from
Florida did you you did yes I did and
you took the workshop as soon as you got
here
the next day I came in making workshop
and then that evening then I drove after
I left uh your lab then I drove down
into about the middle of North Carolina
and then uh came in yeah that was a heck
of a trip but uh yeah it was very well
worth it believe me okay Bill thank you
so much that's great talk to you soon
okay